OLOWOJAYE ORIMISAN RUFUS

+234 8091314038 | Ife, Osun State, Nigeria rufusolowojaye@gmail.com | https://olowojaye.github.io

SUMMARY

Software Developer with experience in developing responsive and accessible web applications to meet business needs. Proficient with React / NextJS and Express / NodeJS in JavaScript and TypeScript. A first-class engineering graduate and thorough learner open to learning new technologies as problem solutions may require.

CERTIFICATIONS

2022 Responsive Web Design Developer Certification

<u>Issued by freeCodeCamp</u>

2021 IBM Data Science Professional Certificate

Issued by Coursera

EDUCATION

2014-2019 Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Nigeria First Class Honors (4.50/5.0 CGPA)

WORK EXPERIENCE

2022-Current Full Stack Developer

Max Engineering Tutorials, Obafemi Awolowo University, Nigeria

- Developed and maintain the front end and back end of organization's website.
- Coordinate the design team to deliver functionalities with optimum user experience.

2016-Current L

Lead Tutor

Max Engineering Tutorials, Obafemi Awolowo University, Nigeria

- Founded organization to mitigate poor performance in undergraduate engineering courses at the university, reaching averagely 150 students each session.
- Instruct 100+ students on Computer Programming, Engineering Mechanics, and Mathematical Methods, with over 95% achieving target scores every semester.
- Coordinate 12 team members and manage resources to achieve set goals at the minimum cost and inconvenience to students' regular school work.

SKILLS

Web Development: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript

Web Technology Stack: Frontend: React / NextJS; Backend: Express / NodeJS

Styling: SASS, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB ORMs: Prisma, Mongoose

Version Control: Git

Other Languages: Python, Java

Data Science and AI: Python, TensorFlow, SQL

Cloud: IBM Cloud, AWS

Others: Teamwork, Effective Communication

AWARDS

2015-2019 Agbami Special Medical and Engineering Professionals Scholarship Award

A sessional scholarship for select Medical and Engineering undergraduates, conditioned on

sustained academic standing of at least 60% of the university CGPA rating.

2014 Dean's Honors List, Faculty of Technology, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife

In recognition of outstanding academic performance of at least 4.50/5.0 GPA for the semester.